<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Frupidity</title>
    <link>http://www.frupidity.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Frupidity</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 21:30:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.frupidity.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://www.frupidity.com/post/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 21:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.frupidity.com/post/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mr. Frupid and I are part of the early retirement movement. Most people in this movement seem to read blogs like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mrmoneymustache.com/&#34;&gt;Mr. Money Mustache&lt;/a&gt;, suddenly see the error in their ways, and determine how to cut down their spending to achieve early retirement bliss. We, however, are part of a slightly younger and crazier cohort. We started following Mr. Money Mustache back in 2011, when we were still in college, and our response to his wisdom was less a change of mindset than an articulation of our worldview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Frupid and I are high school sweethearts, so we entered adulthood and started creating opinions about how the world works, together. We both considered ourselves frugal before we got together, and Mr. Frupid has always had a special gift for figuring out how to hack a system. These characteristics paired together have evolved over time to make us the rather unusual people we are today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I strongly believe that the frugal lifestyle we have chosen has led to a more fulfilling life and helped me gain independence and freedom in my life choices. Not to mention that we are considering retiring at the ripe old age of 26.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’ve spent a few lines tooting my own horn, I want to take a few steps back. Our journey to financial freedom has been by no means flawless. While most people need a call to action to reign in their lifestyles, we could have probably done without the encouragement. Sure, we have implemented plenty of worthwhile money saving solutions in our lives, but we also &lt;del&gt;have taken&lt;/del&gt; take our need for frugality too far. Fortunately, we learn from and laugh at our mistakes as we search for balance in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that being said, this blog is not about the benefits of frugality. You can find plenty of other blogs if you want to get philosophical on how frugality will improve your life. This blog is also not meant to generate hate on the early retirement movement. Looking back on my adult life, there are no systematic changes I would make to my extremely frugal attitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is about the hilarious mishaps we’ve had in our frugal journey. Not every well intentioned frugal idea should be executed, and when this disconnect happens, only one word can define the results, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;frupidity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>