<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Frupidity</title>
    <link>http://www.frupidity.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Frupidity</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 21:30:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.frupidity.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheap Dates</title>
      <link>http://www.frupidity.com/post/cheapdates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 21:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.frupidity.com/post/cheapdates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I think about the family members Mr. Frupid and I are most similar to, I immediately think of Mr. Frupid&amp;rsquo;s grandparents. They are cheap, stubbornly independent, and indecisive to a fault. Now I realize that I sound like a terrible person for calling out seemingly negative qualities in kind old folks, but I list them with love, because I share all of the same characteristics. These traits tend to drive Mr. Frupid&amp;rsquo;s parents crazy as they&amp;rsquo;re trying to help the grandparents maneuver through old age, but in almost every argument I can at least see where the grandparents are coming from. Actually, I can see myself doing the exact same thing in 60 years. Hell, I&amp;rsquo;m already doing some of the crazy things they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One longstanding part of the grandparents&amp;rsquo; routine is the morning pilgrimage to the Golden Arches. There they order the senior coffee, nothing else, and chat with friends or just each other for hours. The McDonalds senior coffee is a beautiful thing for them - $0.25 for unlimited refills of liquid tar&amp;hellip;I mean gold. I&amp;rsquo;m sure McDonalds established this deal as a way to get seniors in the door in hopes that they would order all of the egg McMuffins their feeble hearts could handle, but Mr. Frupid&amp;rsquo;s grandparents have hacked that system masterfully. I should mention that McDonalds raised the price of the senior coffee a few years ago, and we still haven&amp;rsquo;t heard the end of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;McDonalds obviously isn&amp;rsquo;t alone in offering discounted goods to seniors. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty common practice in restaurants, although when I stop to think about it, I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure why. The naive optimist in me thinks that the discounts are just a way for restaurants to thank the elderly for their lifetime of hard work. The realistic side of me, however, assumes that restaurants recognize that senior citizens are now living on fixed incomes and therefore more prudent with their pocketbooks. Offering a senior discount is a great way to make it look like going to that restaurant is a deal, so restaurants can pull in more customers with a negligible impact to their margins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter the reason, seniors love a good deal. Any time an establishment is giving away cheap or free stuff, you&amp;rsquo;ll always find old people there, even in young Seattle. Why do I know this? Because these establishments are filled with old people plus two - Mr. Frupid and me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a bank near both of our offices that set out to be a neighborhood hang-out when it opened. It has tables, a few couches, and even a fake fireplace for ambience. But the best thing they have to offer is free made-to-order coffee, good coffee! To sweeten the deal, they also offer free cookies on Fridays (pun intended). All of these things are meant for anyone in the community, in theory. However, it is incredibly awkward to walk into an empty bank, make yourself a coffee, and then have a seat, particularly if you&amp;rsquo;re not a customer. So no one does it, except old people and us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think normal people lose their shame/embarrassment filter when they hit old age. Fortunately, it seems Mr. Frupid and I were born without said filter, so we can take advantage of awkward perks for life! So, shame filter absent, we waltz right into this bank, make ourselves coffees and grab multiple cookies just about every Friday. It&amp;rsquo;s actually become one of our most regular dates! The only other people we ever see enjoying the delicious bank coffee are clearly about 50 years older than us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this ritual of ours isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly frupid, it is unusual, at least for people not accustomed to taking advantage of senior discounts. So, I encourage you, try ignoring that shame filter for a day and see what wonderful free while slightly awkward perks await!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airport</title>
      <link>http://www.frupidity.com/post/airport/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 21:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.frupidity.com/post/airport/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you would expect from any city-slicking frugal person, I do not own a car. My bicycle is my main mode of transportation. The perks of getting around by bicycle are enormous. Not only do I get a built in 50 minutes of exercise 5 days a week on my commute to work, but I get to see the world at a slower pace. I’m often the person to tell friends about random places or events in town, thanks to my bicycling adventures. Bill Nye is even a big proponent of &lt;a href=&#34;http://bigthink.com/in-their-own-words/why-i-bike&#34;&gt;bicycle transportation&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, there are definitely times when my lack of a car makes life a little more complicated…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Frupid and I travel to Florida to visit our families every December. Southern Florida is about as far as you can get from Seattle in the continental U.S., so the travel day is painful at the best of times. And this particular year was definitely not the best of times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We (not surprisingly) opted to take the cheapest flight we could find, which left Seattle at 6:00 AM, without thinking through the logistics of getting to the airport. Our default means of getting from our house to the airport is to take a bus and then connect to the light rail, but unfortunately neither run between 1:00 and 5:00 AM. At this point, we were relatively new to Seattle and felt bad pushing our friend/acquaintance relationships into awkward territory by asking for a 3:30 AM ride to the airport. Another option was taking a taxi, but we weren’t interested in paying anywhere near the asking rate. So we settled on what seemed at the time to be the most rational solution - go to bed by 8:00 PM so we could wake up at midnight, walk half a mile in the dark with our rolly suitcases to a less convenient bus, connect to the last light rail of the night downtown, and then hang out at the airport for an extra 4 hours before our flight. What could go wrong?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, for starters, waking up to an alarm about an hour after actually falling asleep feels similar to how I assume attempting to blow dry your hair under water feels, painful and counterproductive. We somehow survived the initial shock though, and got to the bus stop just in time. I was feeling like a master planner at this point, though the feeling was short lived. When we got to the light rail station it was deserted. As we attempted to walk down the still escalator, a janitor came out of nowhere and yelled at us for being in the station, informing us that the last train departed 30 minutes earlier. I couldn’t decide whether I wanted to punch the guy or cry, so I just yelled “but that’s not what Google told us!” as if he would understand that Google is some all-knowing, all powerful God who would defy the &lt;em&gt;schedule&lt;/em&gt; and  make that train appear, damnit! (Sidenote, I’m not actually sure this is an inaccurate depiction of Google, we just may need to wait another few years for that to come to fruition.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, our bloodshot eyes, slow cognition, and nonsensical outburt weren’t quite enough to convince the janitor that we were just high out of our minds, so he felt pity on us and told us that another bus that stopped right outside the station would &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; get us to the airport…&lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever been skeptical of people who take the bus at 1:00 AM, stay skeptical. Especially if that bus goes straight through the shadier neighborhoods in town. For some reason this bus was packed, so Mr. Frupid and I had to split up. I’m pretty sure multiple drug deals went on in the seats around me. Needless to say, I was thoroughly uncomfortable on this journey. But we survived, and about an hour later we were at the final stop, &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; to the airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were actually only about a mile away from the airport at this point. Unfortunately, it was a mile of large highway with plenty of run-down hotels advertising “hourly rentals” and the occasional lady of the night lingering out front. But alas, we walked our trusty rolly suitcases through sketch-ville. We couldn’t help but giggle at the thought of walking onto airport property - we doubted that anyone had tried it before. But we were going to do it, and at 2:00 AM to boot! About halfway to the airport, we spotted the car rental depot and noticed the office was open. We decided to go in and ask for a lift to the departures area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were two employees in the office. The woman working clearly wasn’t pleased to have her middle of the night lull interrupted and wanted nothing to do with us. Fortunately, though, the man working felt pity on us and agreed to drive us to the departures area. So at about 2:30 AM, more than 2 hours after our 20 minute drive of an adventure started, we arrived in style via the car rental shuttle. After that, the experience was pretty smooth sailing. We unsuccessfully attempted to nap in airport chairs with our sunglasses on for 2 hours then started the “normal” travel experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will concede that it absolutely would have made more sense to just take the red-eye or chalk up the $50 for a cab. On the other hand, we were still young and a night of missed sleep (and a few sketchy encounters) didn’t kill us. One thing is for sure, we’ll never forget that night!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://www.frupidity.com/post/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 21:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.frupidity.com/post/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mr. Frupid and I are part of the early retirement movement. Most people in this movement seem to read blogs like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mrmoneymustache.com/&#34;&gt;Mr. Money Mustache&lt;/a&gt;, suddenly see the error in their ways, and determine how to cut down their spending to achieve early retirement bliss. We, however, are part of a slightly younger and crazier cohort. We started following Mr. Money Mustache back in 2011, when we were still in college, and our response to his wisdom was less a change of mindset than an articulation of our worldview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Frupid and I are high school sweethearts, so we entered adulthood and started creating opinions about how the world works, together. We both considered ourselves frugal before we got together, and Mr. Frupid has always had a special gift for figuring out how to hack a system. These characteristics paired together have evolved over time to make us the rather unusual people we are today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I strongly believe that the frugal lifestyle we have chosen has led to a more fulfilling life and helped me gain independence and freedom in my life choices. Not to mention that we are considering retiring at the ripe old age of 26.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’ve spent a few lines tooting my own horn, I want to take a few steps back. Our journey to financial freedom has been by no means flawless. While most people need a call to action to reign in their lifestyles, we could have probably done without the encouragement. Sure, we have implemented plenty of worthwhile money saving solutions in our lives, but we also &lt;del&gt;have taken&lt;/del&gt; take our need for frugality too far. Fortunately, we learn from and laugh at our mistakes as we search for balance in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that being said, this blog is not about the benefits of frugality. You can find plenty of other blogs if you want to get philosophical on how frugality will improve your life. This blog is also not meant to generate hate on the early retirement movement. Looking back on my adult life, there are no systematic changes I would make to my extremely frugal attitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is about the hilarious mishaps we’ve had in our frugal journey. Not every well intentioned frugal idea should be executed, and when this disconnect happens, only one word can define the results, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;frupidity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>